<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Home on Buy A Home 101 - Your Guide to Homeownership</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Home on Buy A Home 101 - Your Guide to Homeownership</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 20 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>15 First-Time Home Buyer Tips</title>
      <link>/categories/first-time-buyers/first-time-home-buyer-tips/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/categories/first-time-buyers/first-time-home-buyer-tips/</guid>
      <description>Buying your first home is a major milestone — and it can feel overwhelming. But with the right information, you can navigate the process with confidence.&#xA;1. Invest in Homeownership Education Before diving in, take time to understand the basics:&#xA;A mortgage is a loan for buying a house that you pay back over time with interest Most buyers put down 3%–20% upfront and finance the rest 30-year mortgages offer lower payments but more interest over time 15-year mortgages have higher payments but save thousands in interest Consider taking a home buying education class — some down payment assistance programs actually require it.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Boost Your Credit Score Before Buying a Home</title>
      <link>/categories/credit-tips/boost-credit-score/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/categories/credit-tips/boost-credit-score/</guid>
      <description>Your credit score directly affects your mortgage rate. A 720 score vs. 680 could mean 0.5% - 1% lower rate — that&amp;rsquo;s $100+ per month on a $300,000 loan.&#xA;Here&amp;rsquo;s how to boost your score before applying.&#xA;Quick Wins: 30-60 Days 1. Check Your Reports Get free reports at AnnualCreditReport.com. Dispute errors — they happen more often than you think.&#xA;2. Pay Down Credit Cards Utilization matters. Keep balances below 30% of limits.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Buy Investment Properties with No Income Verification</title>
      <link>/categories/investment-properties/dscr-loans-no-income-verification/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/categories/investment-properties/dscr-loans-no-income-verification/</guid>
      <description>Want to buy rental properties but don&amp;rsquo;t want to jump through hoops proving your personal income? DSCR loans might be exactly what you need.&#xA;What is a DSCR Loan? DSCR = Debt Service Coverage Ratio&#xA;Instead of verifying your personal income (W-2s, tax returns, pay stubs), lenders look at whether the property itself generates enough cash flow to cover the mortgage.&#xA;The Simple Formula: Monthly Rent &amp;gt; Monthly Mortgage Payment = Approved If the property rents for more than it costs to finance, you qualify.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Closing Costs Explained: What You&#39;ll Actually Pay</title>
      <link>/categories/first-time-buyers/closing-costs-explained/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/categories/first-time-buyers/closing-costs-explained/</guid>
      <description>Your down payment isn&amp;rsquo;t the only cash you need. Closing costs are 3-6% of your loan amount — and they&amp;rsquo;re due at settlement.&#xA;What Are Closing Costs? Closing costs are fees for services required to complete your loan. They cover:&#xA;Lender fees Third-party services Government recording Title insurance Typical Cost Breakdown On a $350,000 loan (~$10,500 - $21,000 total):&#xA;Fee Typical Cost Loan Origination 0.5% - 1% ($1,750 - $3,500) Appraisal $400 - $600 Credit Report $30 - $50 Title Insurance $800 - $2,500 Title Search $200 - $400 Attorney Fees $500 - $1,500 Survey $300 - $800 Recording Fees $50 - $150 Escrow Deposits 2-6 months property taxes &amp;amp; insurance Discount Points 0 - 2% (optional) Prepaid Interest Varies How to Reduce Closing Costs 1.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Down Payment Assistance: Free Money to Buy Your Home</title>
      <link>/categories/first-time-buyers/down-payment-assistance/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/categories/first-time-buyers/down-payment-assistance/</guid>
      <description>Saving for a down payment is the #1 hurdle for first-time home buyers. But did you know there are hundreds of programs that can help?&#xA;What is Down Payment Assistance? Down payment assistance (DPA) programs provide:&#xA;Grants — Money you never have to repay Forgivable loans — No repayment if you stay in the home long enough Low-interest loans — Affordable second mortgages Tax credits — Savings on your tax bill Who Qualifies?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>FHA Loans: The Good, The Bad, and The Ugly Truth</title>
      <link>/categories/loan-programs/fha-loans-good-bad-ugly/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/categories/loan-programs/fha-loans-good-bad-ugly/</guid>
      <description>FHA loans are marketed as &amp;ldquo;easy to qualify&amp;rdquo; — and they are. But there&amp;rsquo;s a catch that catches many borrowers off guard: mandatory mortgage insurance that doesn&amp;rsquo;t go away.&#xA;The FHA Promise 3.5% down payment Credit scores as low as 580 (10% down if 500-579) More flexible on credit events (bankruptcies, foreclosures) Assumable (great when rates rise) Sounds great, right? Here&amp;rsquo;s the catch.&#xA;The Mortgage Insurance Problem Upfront MIP 0.15% of loan amount (most borrowers) 1.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Lowest Rate ≠ Lowest Payment: The Hidden Cost Most Borrowers Miss</title>
      <link>/categories/loan-programs/lowest-rate-vs-lowest-payment/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/categories/loan-programs/lowest-rate-vs-lowest-payment/</guid>
      <description>Everyone wants the lowest interest rate. That&amp;rsquo;s natural — it&amp;rsquo;s what mortgage ads talk about. But lowest rate doesn&amp;rsquo;t always mean lowest payment.&#xA;Here&amp;rsquo;s a secret the industry doesn&amp;rsquo;t advertise: Mortgage insurance can add 1% or more to your actual rate.&#xA;The Problem with &amp;ldquo;Rate Shopping&amp;rdquo; When borrowers ask &amp;ldquo;What&amp;rsquo;s your rate?&amp;rdquo;, they&amp;rsquo;re thinking about the note rate. But there&amp;rsquo;s another cost hiding in plain sight:&#xA;Private Mortgage Insurance (PMI)</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Self-Employed? You Can Still Buy a Home</title>
      <link>/categories/loan-programs/self-employed-home-buying/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/categories/loan-programs/self-employed-home-buying/</guid>
      <description>Being self-employed has perks — but when it comes to getting a mortgage, it can feel like an uphill battle. Good news: There are options designed specifically for entrepreneurs and business owners.&#xA;The Freddie Mac 5-Year Rule Here&amp;rsquo;s something many borrowers don&amp;rsquo;t know about:&#xA;If you&amp;rsquo;ve been in business for 5+ years, Freddie Mac may only require 1 year of tax returns instead of 2.&#xA;This is a game-changer for established business owners who had a slower first year or are investing heavily in growth.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>VA Loans: The Most Underrated Benefit for Veterans</title>
      <link>/categories/loan-programs/va-loans-veterans/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/categories/loan-programs/va-loans-veterans/</guid>
      <description>If you&amp;rsquo;re a veteran or active-duty service member, the VA loan is probably the best mortgage product available. Period.&#xA;Why VA Loans Rock 0% down — Zero. Nothing. Buy a home with no money down No PMI — Unlike conventional and FHA, no monthly mortgage insurance Competitive rates — Usually lower than conventional Flexible credit — More forgiving than conventional Assumable — Transfer the loan to another eligible veteran No prepayment penalty — Pay off early, no fees Who Qualifies?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Post 3</title>
      <link>/posts/post-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Mar 2023 11:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/post-3/</guid>
      <description>Occaecat aliqua consequat laborum ut ex aute aliqua culpa quis irure esse magna dolore quis. Proident fugiat labore eu laboris officia Lorem enim. Ipsum occaecat cillum ut tempor id sint aliqua incididunt nisi incididunt reprehenderit. Voluptate ad minim sint est aute aliquip esse occaecat tempor officia qui sunt. Aute ex ipsum id ut in est velit est laborum incididunt. Aliqua qui id do esse sunt eiusmod id deserunt eu nostrud aute sit ipsum.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Post 2</title>
      <link>/posts/post-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Feb 2023 10:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/post-2/</guid>
      <description>Anim eiusmod irure incididunt sint cupidatat. Incididunt irure irure irure nisi ipsum do ut quis fugiat consectetur proident cupidatat incididunt cillum. Dolore voluptate occaecat qui mollit laborum ullamco et. Ipsum laboris officia anim laboris culpa eiusmod ex magna ex cupidatat anim ipsum aute. Mollit aliquip occaecat qui sunt velit ut cupidatat reprehenderit enim sunt laborum. Velit veniam in officia nulla adipisicing ut duis officia.&#xA;Exercitation voluptate irure in irure tempor mollit Lorem nostrud ad officia.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Post 1</title>
      <link>/posts/post-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Jan 2023 09:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/post-1/</guid>
      <description>Tempor proident minim aliquip reprehenderit dolor et ad anim Lorem duis sint eiusmod. Labore ut ea duis dolor. Incididunt consectetur proident qui occaecat incididunt do nisi Lorem. Tempor do laborum elit laboris excepteur eiusmod do. Eiusmod nisi excepteur ut amet pariatur adipisicing Lorem.&#xA;Occaecat nulla excepteur dolore excepteur duis eiusmod ullamco officia anim in voluptate ea occaecat officia. Cillum sint esse velit ea officia minim fugiat. Elit ea esse id aliquip pariatur cupidatat id duis minim incididunt ea ea.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Get Pre-Qualified</title>
      <link>/prequalify/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/prequalify/</guid>
      <description>Start Your Pre-Qualification Fill out the form below and a mortgage professional will contact you within 24 hours.&#xA;&amp;lt;div class=&amp;quot;form-group&amp;quot;&amp;gt; &amp;lt;label for=&amp;quot;email&amp;quot;&amp;gt;Email Address&amp;lt;/label&amp;gt; &amp;lt;input type=&amp;quot;email&amp;quot; id=&amp;quot;email&amp;quot; name=&amp;quot;email&amp;quot; required placeholder=&amp;quot;john@email.com&amp;quot;&amp;gt; &amp;lt;/div&amp;gt; &amp;lt;div class=&amp;quot;form-group&amp;quot;&amp;gt; &amp;lt;label for=&amp;quot;phone&amp;quot;&amp;gt;Phone Number&amp;lt;/label&amp;gt; &amp;lt;input type=&amp;quot;tel&amp;quot; id=&amp;quot;phone&amp;quot; name=&amp;quot;phone&amp;quot; required placeholder=&amp;quot;(555) 123-4567&amp;quot;&amp;gt; &amp;lt;/div&amp;gt; &amp;lt;div class=&amp;quot;form-group&amp;quot;&amp;gt; &amp;lt;label for=&amp;quot;loantype&amp;quot;&amp;gt;Loan Type Interested In&amp;lt;/label&amp;gt; &amp;lt;select id=&amp;quot;loantype&amp;quot; name=&amp;quot;loantype&amp;quot;&amp;gt; &amp;lt;option value=&amp;quot;&amp;quot;&amp;gt;Select a loan type&amp;lt;/option&amp;gt; &amp;lt;option value=&amp;quot;purchase&amp;quot;&amp;gt;Purchase a Home&amp;lt;/option&amp;gt; &amp;lt;option value=&amp;quot;refinance&amp;quot;&amp;gt;Refinance&amp;lt;/option&amp;gt; &amp;lt;option value=&amp;quot;first-time&amp;quot;&amp;gt;First-Time Home Buyer&amp;lt;/option&amp;gt; &amp;lt;option value=&amp;quot;investment&amp;quot;&amp;gt;Investment Property&amp;lt;/option&amp;gt; &amp;lt;option value=&amp;quot;self-employed&amp;quot;&amp;gt;Self-Employed / 1099&amp;lt;/option&amp;gt; &amp;lt;option value=&amp;quot;not-sure&amp;quot;&amp;gt;Not Sure Yet&amp;lt;/option&amp;gt; &amp;lt;/select&amp;gt; &amp;lt;/div&amp;gt; &amp;lt;div class=&amp;quot;form-group&amp;quot;&amp;gt; &amp;lt;label for=&amp;quot;price&amp;quot;&amp;gt;Estimated Home Price&amp;lt;/label&amp;gt; &amp;lt;select id=&amp;quot;price&amp;quot; name=&amp;quot;price&amp;quot;&amp;gt; &amp;lt;option value=&amp;quot;&amp;quot;&amp;gt;Select a range&amp;lt;/option&amp;gt; &amp;lt;option value=&amp;quot;under-200k&amp;quot;&amp;gt;Under $200,000&amp;lt;/option&amp;gt; &amp;lt;option value=&amp;quot;200k-350k&amp;quot;&amp;gt;$200,000 - $350,000&amp;lt;/option&amp;gt; &amp;lt;option value=&amp;quot;350k-500k&amp;quot;&amp;gt;$350,000 - $500,000&amp;lt;/option&amp;gt; &amp;lt;option value=&amp;quot;500k-750k&amp;quot;&amp;gt;$500,000 - $750,000&amp;lt;/option&amp;gt; &amp;lt;option value=&amp;quot;750k+&amp;quot;&amp;gt;$750,000+&amp;lt;/option&amp;gt; &amp;lt;/select&amp;gt; &amp;lt;/div&amp;gt; &amp;lt;div class=&amp;quot;form-group&amp;quot;&amp;gt; &amp;lt;label for=&amp;quot;message&amp;quot;&amp;gt;Any Questions or Comments?</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
